# Joshua A. Leath

♠ Newark, OH
Material joshua.leath@icloud.com
Image: Image: Image of the properties of the pro

### **PROFILE**

I am a software engineer with multiple years of experience with JavaScript, Ruby, Go and various frameworks. I am a cocreator of Chimera  $\mathscr{D}$ , an open-source tool for automating canary deployments of containerized microservices.

## **SKILLS**

Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, Go

Cloud

AWS (Lambda, S3, ECR, ECS, VPC, App Mesh, CloudWatch, SDK, CDK, CloudFormation), Heroku, DigitalOcean

**Frameworks** 

Node, Express, React/Redux, Sinatra

Other Technologies

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Linux, HTTP, REST APIs, Git/GitHub, Docker, HTML/CSS, NGINX

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2022 - present

**Co-creator, Software Engineer,** Chimera - chimera-deploy.dev *⊘* 

- Researched, designed, prototyped and implemented Chimera, a tool for performing automated canary deployments of microservices hosted on AWS Elastic Container Service using AWS App Mesh for inter-service communication
- Utilized AWS CloudWatch and Prometheus to monitor metrics related to deployment
- Designed and implemented an Express backend that can be used to create and configure AWS resources
- Utilized server-sent events to pass live updates and metrics to a user interface
- Designed and implemented a locally-hosted React/Redux frontend to configure and begin deployments
- Presented a live tech-talk about Chimera
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study

2020 - 2022

#### Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-employed

- Developed open-source software using Node.js, Express, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, React/Redux, vanilla JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Meridian a deep space object tracker built with React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB and deployed on a DigitalOcean Droplet
- Chip8-js a chip-8 interpreter for the browser built with JavaScript. Includes a debugger with a memory inspector, breakpoints and a code disassembler
- SchemeEdit a browser based editor for the Scheme programming language built with JavaScript
- Requesto Webhook and HTTP request visualizer for viewing and debugging network communication built using Node, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB

2017 - 2020

**Reports Specialist,** Charter Communications

• Received the Charter Gold award in 2019, an annual recognition of the top performers across the organization

# **EDUCATION**

2020 - 2022

**Launch School** 

Multi-year, full-stack software engineering curriculum emphasizing mastery of programming fundamentals and problem-solving

2015

BS in Computer Information Technology, Southern New Hampshire University